tapproject.org 2018-08-16

# Privacy Statement | UNICEF USA

UNICEF USA is dedicated to honoring the privacy and wishes of our supporters at all times. Following are details about our privacy policies, including what type of information is gathered and tracked, how the information is used and with whom the information is shared. This privacy statement does not apply to information gathered by UNICEF Market which has its own privacy policy located at <http://www.market.unicefusa.org/customerservice/#privacy-policy>. The statement was last updated on March 18, 2015. Please visit this page from time to time and check for any updates.

### Contact us

This website is owned by the United States Fund for UNICEF. Please feel free to [contact us](https://www.unicefusa.org/about/contact "Contact the UNICEF USA") in any of the following ways if you have questions or concerns. 

Postal mail:  
 UNICEF USA  
 125 Maiden Lane  
 New York, NY 10038

 Phone:  
 1.800.FOR.KIDS

 FAX:  
 212.779.1679

Email:  

### Collection of Personal Data

UNICEF USA only collects and maintains personal information that is sent to us directly from an individual or company. This information is obtained from direct mail, telemarketing, face to face and other forms of solicitation and from the following places on our website:

  * Donation and pledge forms
  * Registration forms
  * eCommerce/product fulfillment forms
  * eNews registration
  * ShopUNICEF registration
  * Volunteer registration
  * Friends-Asking-Friends registration
  * Trick-or-Treat Online registration
  * Take Action advocacy form
  * Email messages sent directly to our attention
  * Contact Us form
  * Online surveys

You can visit [www.unicefusa.org](https://www.unicefusa.org/ "Help Children :: Humanitarian Aid & Emergency Relief") without telling us who you are and without revealing any information about yourself. However, to access certain portions of the website, you may have to submit information such as a user-id and password, or you may have to provide personal information such as your name, address and email.

To complete online transactions, you will be asked for your address, email and credit card information. This required information is necessary for us to process transactions, protect you against credit card fraud and contact you should the need arise in administering your account.

Our site may contain surveys, trivia games and other forms for collecting information.

### Information Security and Quality

UNICEF USA intends to protect the quality and integrity of your personally identifiable information. We have implemented appropriate physical, technical and organizational measures, including industry-standard encryption for transmission of credit card information, to help keep your information secure, accurate, current and complete.

Donations made on the [www.unicefusa.org](https://www.unicefusa.org/ "Help Children :: Humanitarian Aid & Emergency Relief") website are secure to the fullest extent possible. We use strong 256-bit encryption through TLS (Transport Layer Security -- formerly SSL or Secure Sockets Layer technology). TLS protects information as it is transferred through the Internet.  Beginning July 1, 2016 some older web browsers may no longer load [www.unicefusa.org](https://www.unicefusa.org/). Therefore, we recommend upgrading to a modern web browser, such as Google Chrome, Safari, Firefox or Edge. 

You can recognize secure web pages by checking for the secure symbol at the bottom of your browser screen. For most browsers, this symbol is either a lock or a key. When the lock symbol appears to be locked, the page is secure. When it appears to be unlocked, the page is insecure.

**Website Traffic Information**  
When you arrive at or leave the UNICEF USA website, we automatically receive the web address of the site that you came from or are going to. We also collect information on which pages you visit while you are on our site, the type of browser you use and the times you access our site. We use this information only to try to better understand visitor preferences.

### "Cookies"

We sometimes use "cookies" to collect anonymous information from visits to our sites to help us provide better service. A cookie is an element of data that a website can send to your browser, which may then be stored on your system. We may use this data to analyze trends and statistics and to help us provide better service, but we do so in ways that keep the information anonymous. In order to improve the quality of our communications, we may also from time to time share such anonymous information with certain third parties, such as our advertising and media vendors, including, without limitation, advertising.com.

You can set your browser to notify you before you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether to accept it. You can also set your browser to turn off cookies. If you do so, however, some areas of our site may not function properly.

### Disclosure to Third Parties

UNICEF USA does not rent, exchange or sell the email addresses or credit card information of our supporters. However, from time to time we make our postal mailing list available to other worthy organizations. If you prefer that your postal information not be shared, please write to us at [webmaster@unicefusa.org](mailto:webmaster@unicefusa.org) and we will honor your wishes immediately.

UNICEF USA  engages third party vendors for purposes of solicitation, fulfillment and other consulting services. The contracts with these third party vendors include a strict confidentiality clause that prohibits use and disclosure of confidential information received or obtained during the performance of the agreements or in the course of providing such services, and carries damages, penalties and other injunctive remedies for a vendor’s violation of these confidentiality requirements.

We may also share donor and campaign information with the national and local offices of our affiliate organizations, and we publish a list of top fundraising schools and groups annually on the UNICEF USA's website. If you prefer that we do not include your name or the name of your organization in these cases, please write to us at [webmaster@unicefusa.org](mailto:webmaster@unicefusa.org).

### Email

UNICEF USA adheres to a strict anti-spam policy, making it easy for our eNews subscribers to unsubscribe. UNICEF USA may also provides email marketing tools to some website visitors who have created personal web pages. These tools provide convenient ways to communicate with friends and family on a personal level; they are not designed for sending out bulk emails.

### Personalized Webpages

UNICEF USA may allow some constituents to create web content (including email) that brings visitors to personalized webpages. Such personal webpages, as well as the individual associated with the page, are readily identifiable. By clicking on a link and going to a personal webpage you are agreeing to let the U.S. Fund collect information about your session visits. We use this information for aggregate statistical analysis only. Transactions made via personalized webpages are subject to the same privacy policies as all other transactions made on the U.S. Fund site.

### Children's Online Privacy Protection

UNICEF USA is especially concerned about ensuring the privacy of children online. We are therefore committed to comply with applicable laws and requirements, such as the U.S. Children's Online Privacy Protection Act.

Please note that we try to ensure that all our activities (particularly the annual Trick-or-Treat for UNICEF campaign) are coordinated by an adult and therefore make every effort to send information to adults only. If you are aware that a child has provided his or her name to us, please email [webmaster@unicefusa.org](mailto:webmaster@unicefusa.org) to provide the child's name along with a supervising adult's contact information.

**Links to Other Websites**  
UNICEF USA website contains links to other sites. UNICEF USA is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites.

### "Donor Bill of Rights"

UNICEF USA believes in the rights of donors and subscribes to the Donor Bill of Rights. This statement of rights was developed by the following organizations: the American Association of Fund Raising Counsel, Association for Healthcare Philanthropy, Council for Advancement and Support of Education, and National Society of Fund Raising Executives. The full text of the Donor Bill of Rights follows.

"Philanthropy is based on voluntary action for the common good. It is a tradition of giving and sharing that is primary to the quality of life. To assure that philanthropy merits the respect and trust of the general public, and that donors and prospective donors can have full confidence in the not-for-profit organizations and causes they are asked to support, we declare that all donors have these rights:

  1. To be informed of the organization's mission, of the way the organization intends to use donated resources, and of its capacity to use donations effectively for their intended purposes.
  2. To be informed of the identity of those serving on the organization's governing board, and to expect the board to exercise prudent judgment in its stewardship responsibilities.
  3. To have access to the organization's most recent financial statements.
  4. To be assured their gifts will be used for the purposes for which they were given.
  5. To receive appropriate acknowledgement and recognition.
  6. To be assured that information about their donations is handled with respect and with confidentiality to the extent provided by law.
  7. To expect that all relationships with individuals representing organizations of interest to the donor will be professional in nature.
  8. To be informed whether those seeking donations are volunteers, employees of the organization or hired solicitors.
  9. To have the opportunity for their names to be deleted from mailing lists that an organization may intend to share.
  10. To feel free to ask questions when making a donation and to receive prompt, truthful and forthright answers."
